Guide to the Partners for Livable Communities records, 1960-2012
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 8: Photographs, 1970s-2010s; (19 boxes)
  - Minnesota: St. Paul, 1980s (Box 171, Folder 33)
  - Kansas: Tulsa, 1990s (Box 171, Folder 34)
  - Utah, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Virginia: Alexandria, 1981-1987 (Box 172, Folder 2)
  - Virginia: Northern Virginia, 1983 (Box 172, Folder 3)
  - Virginia: Richmond, 1981-1984 (Box 172, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, 1981 (Box 172, Folder 5)
  - Washington: Seattle, 1984-1990 (Box 172, Folder 6)
  - Wisconsin: Milwaukee, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 7)
  - Vermont: landscapes, roads, and bridges, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 8)
  - various locations, 1984-1986 (Box 172, Folder 9)
  - International: Mexico, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 10)
  - Archeology, 1980s-1990s (Box 172, Folder 11)
  - Public housing, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 12)
  - Historic Restoration, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 13)
  - Zoos, aquariums, and botanical gardens, 1991 (Box 172, Folder 14)
  - Model of the Museum of Flight, 1990s (Box 172, Folder 15)
  - Japanese Art, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 16)
  - Thomas Hart Benton's America Today, 1984 (Box 172, Folder 17)
  - Public Transportation, 1981-1982 (Box 172, Folder 18)
  - Trains, 1981 (Box 172, Folder 19)
  - Roads, 1980s (Box 172, Folder 20)
  - Waterfronts, 1982 (Box 172, Folder 21)
  - Water and underwater archeology, 1984-1988 (Box 172, Folder 22)
  - PLACE magazine images, 1987 (Box 172, Folder 23)
  - Buildings, 1984 (Box 172, Folder 24)
  - Dance, 1980s (Box 173, Folder 1)
  - Culture, 1980s (Box 173, Folder 2)
  - Music, 1970s-1980s (Box 173, Folder 3)
  - Pictures from january 1986 and June 1988 reports and 1992 campign, 1986-1992 (Box 173, Folder 4)
  - Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 1970s (Box 173, Folder 5)
  - Poland, 1970s (Box 173, Folder 6)
  - City As A Stage, 1970s (Box 173, Folder 7)
  - Build Arts/Built Arts exhibit (ACA/NEA - 1981) (Box 173, Folder 8)
  - New York, 1980-1984 (Box 173, Folder 9)
  - North Carolina: Asheville, 1988 (Box 173, Folder 10)
  - New York, 1970s-1980s (Box 173, Folder 11)
  - Citicorp Building, New York City, 1980s (Box 173, Folder 12)
  - New York City, 1980s (Box 173, Folder 13)
  - PLP slides, 1970s-1980s (Box 173, Folder 14)
  - unidentified pictures, 1980s-1990s (Box 173, Folder 15)
  - Massachussetts: Boston - Old City Hall, 1983 (Box 173, Folder 16)
  - Massachussetts, 1980s (Box 173, Folder 17)
  - Massachussetts: Newbury, 1980s (Box 173, Folder 18)
  - Massachussetts: Cambridge, 1983 (Box 173, Folder 19)
  - Massachussetts: Chelsey - Bellingham, 1980s-1990s (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Various locations, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 2)
  - Massachussetts, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 3)
  - Massachussetts, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 4)
  - Michigan, 1990 (Box 174, Folder 5)
  - Michigan: Detroit, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 6)
  - Minnesota, 1980s-1990s (Box 174, Folder 7)
  - Mississippi, 1983 (Box 174, Folder 8)
  - Minnesota: St. Paul, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 9)
  - Missouri: Kansas City, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 10)
  - Missouri, 1981-1984 (Box 174, Folder 11)
  - Missour: St. Louis, 1981-1984 (Box 174, Folder 12)
  - New Jersey: Patterson, 1980-1983 (Box 174, Folder 13)
  - New Jersey, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 14)
  - New Mexico, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 15)
  - Ohio: Dayton, 1985 (Box 174, Folder 16)
  - Ohio: Cincinnati, 1982 (Box 174, Folder 17)
  - Ohio: Cleveland, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 18)
  - Oklahoma: Oklahoma City, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 19)
  - Oklahoma: Tulsa, 1984 (Box 174, Folder 20)
  - Oregon: Eugene, 1983 (Box 174, Folder 21)
  - Oregon: Portland, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania: Philedelphia, 1990s (Box 174, Folder 23)
  - Pennsylvania: Pittsburgh, 1981-1984 (Box 174, Folder 24)
  - Pennsylvania: Pittsburgh - Sculpture Park, 1984 (Box 174, Folder 25)
  - Pennsylvania: Pittsburgh - Mellon Square, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 26)
  - Pennsylvania: Pittsburgh - Station Square, 1974 (Box 174, Folder 27)
  - Rhode Island: Pawtucket, 1980s (Box 174, Folder 28)
  - Art, 1980s (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - America's Most Livable Communities, 2004 (Box 175, Folder 2)
  - Celebration of Vision and Community Spirit photo directory, 1990s (Box 175, Folder 3)
  - St. John's Recreation Center, 1990s (Box 175, Folder 4)
  - various headshots, 1990s-2000s (Box 175, Folder 5)
  - photos for 25 year report, 2000 (Box 175, Folder 6)
  - City Assets, 1984 (Box 175, Folder 7)
  - City Assets, 1980s (Box 175, Folder 8)
  - The Freedom Forum, 1997 (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - "Crossing the Line" Conference, 1990s (Box 176, Folder 2)
  - City Assets Conference, 1985-1988 (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - Crossing the Line Conference, 1990s (Box 177, Folder 2)
  - DC Arts Alive Forum, 1990s (Box 177, Folder 3)
  - Downtown in America Awards, 1996 (Box 177, Folder 4)
  - Event in Chattanooga, 1980s (Box 177, Folder 5)
  - Events with Bob McNulty, 1987-1990 (Box 177, Folder 6)
  - Forum on Nature and the Economics of a City at Brooklyn Botanical Gardens, 1984 (Box 177, Folder 7)
  - Founders Awards, 1997 (Box 177, Folder 8)
  - Founding Meeting, 1977 (Box 177, Folder 9)
  - German Marshall Fund/Partners European Tours, 1982-1984 (Box 177, Folder 10)
  - Greenbrier Forum - Partners Council, 1984 (Box 177, Folder 11)
  - Hartford Cultural Planning Charrette, 1984 (Box 177, Folder 12)
  - PLP Board Meeting, 1990 (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - Putting Families First Forum, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 2)
  - Revone Wedding - London, 1998 (Box 178, Folder 3)
  - Sorento Charrette, 1990s (Box 178, Folder 4)
  - Strasburg Forum, 1982-1984 (Box 178, Folder 5)
  - Third Decade Reunion and Honors Program, 1990s (Box 178, Folder 6)
  - Unknown Events, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 7)
  - Wingspread, 1981 (Box 178, Folder 8)
  - Alden, Richard L., 1980s (Box 178, Folder 9)
  - Armstrong, David L., 1990s (Box 178, Folder 10)
  - Bacon, Karen, 1981 (Box 178, Folder 11)
  - Bartley, Anne, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 12)
  - Biddle, Livingston, 1970s (Box 178, Folder 13)
  - Binder, Gordon, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 14)
  - Birde, Majorie, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustees members, 1988 (Box 178, Folder 16)
  - Board of Trustees members, 1989 (Box 178, Folder 17)
  - Brademus, John, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 18)
  - Brady, Geroge, 1990s (Box 178, Folder 19)
  - Brambilla, Roberto, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 20)
  - Chatfield-Taylor, Adele, 1982 (Box 178, Folder 21)
  - Cisneros, Harry, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 22)
  - Cloar, Jim, 1985 (Box 178, Folder 23)
  - Cody, Iron Eyes, 1981 (Box 178, Folder 24)
  - Coleman, Pope, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 25)
  - Cook, John, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 26)
  - Coors, Holly, 1991 (Box 178, Folder 27)
  - Costa, Steve, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 28)
  - Deane, Frederick, Jr., 1980s (Box 178, Folder 29)
  - Dowling, Bruce, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 30)
  - Dwyer, Kathy, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 31)
  - Eckardt, Wolfe Von, 1981 (Box 178, Folder 32)
  - Fayman, Dana, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 33)
  - Fleming, Richard, 1980s-1990s (Box 178, Folder 34)
  - Fleming, Ronald Lee, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 35)
  - Ford, O'Neil, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 36)
  - Frederick, Bill, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 37)
  - Garrett, Wilbur, 1990s (Box 178, Folder 38)
  - Geddes, Robert, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 39)
  - Glaser, Milton, 1980s (Box 178, Folder 40)
- Series 9: Audiovisual, 1977-2011; (11 boxes)
  Series 9 contains audiovisual materials. There are a variety of videotapes, cassettes, compact discs and diskettes that Partners created and gathered. Most of the materials are relevant to the various sponsored programs that Partners of Livable Communities initiated.
  - American Mayors in Europe, 1982 (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - Bridge Builders I Awards, 1997 (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - Bridge Builders II Awards, 1998 (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Bridge Builders IV Awards, 2000 (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - City Assets, 1985 (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Cleveland City Club Forum, 1984 (Box 144, Folder 6)
  - Community, Redevelopment, Economic, 1998 (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - Cultural Planning Bridges to Community Renewal, 1988 (Box 144, Folder 8)
  - Horizons for the 1990's - Beyond the Livable City, 1989 (Box 144, Folder 9)
    2 copies
  - Keynote: Breakfast - Clarence Page, 1989 (Box 144, Folder 10)
  - Mining Your Community's Assets, 1989 (Box 144, Folder 11)
    part 1 of 2; 2 copies
  - Mining Your Community's Assets, 1989 (Box 144, Folder 12)
    part 2 of 2; 2 copies
  - Smithsonian Lecture Series, 1987 (Box 144, Folder 13)
  - America's Most Livable Communities Poster, 2000 (Box 144, Folder 14)
  - Crossing the Line: National Leadership Forum, 1999 (Box 144, Folder 15)
  - Best Practices, 2000 (Box 144, Folder 16)
  - City Assets: Quality of Life in the Economic Life of the City, 1985 (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Renewable American Community Conference: Local Solutions to National Problems, 1992 (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Renewable American Community Conference: Local Solutions to National Problems, 1992 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    5 copies
  - After Sunday: Patners for Sacred Places, undated (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - Angel in the Village: The Journey of Lily Yeh, Artist and Activist, 1998 (Box 147, Folder 2)
  - Arts in a Living Downtown: The Next Step, 1998 (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Arts in a Living Downtown: The Next Step, 1998 (Box 147, Folder 4)
    part 2 of 2
  - ArtShow: Youth and Community Development, 2000, 1992 (Box 147, Folder 5)
  - Awards Dinner at Union Station, 1995 (Box 147, Folder 6)
  - Back from the Brink: Saving America's Communities By Design, 1995 (Box 147, Folder 7)
  - Becoming Good Neighbors: Enriching America's Communities By Design, 1996 (Box 147, Folder 8)
  - Blueprint 2000, 1995 (Box 147, Folder 9)
  - Bob McNulty Interview, undated (Box 147, Folder 10)
  - Bridge Builder IV Awards, 2000 (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - Bridge Builders IV Awards: Kathy Morgan, 2000 (Box 148, Folder 2)
  - Cathy Bessant Tribute to Vickie Tassan, 2006 (Box 148, Folder 3)
  - Chattanooga: A Community With Vision, undated (Box 148, Folder 4)
  - Chicago Cultural Plan, 1987 (Box 148, Folder 5)
  - City Assets, 2000 (Box 148, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut Network: Your Daily Connection to State Government, 2000 (Box 148, Folder 7)
  - Cornerstones Community Partnership, undated (Box 148, Folder 8)
  - Culture Builds Florida, 2004 (Box 148, Folder 9)
    part 1 of 2
  - Culture Builds Florida, 2004 (Box 148, Folder 10)
  - Doing More With Less: Challenges of the 90's, undated (Box 148, Folder 11)
  - Grace Hill: Neightbors Helping Neighbors, 1994 (Box 148, Folder 12)
  - July '64: A Documentation of a Racial Riot in Rochester, 2004 (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - Library Without Walls, 1990 (Box 149, Folder 2)
  - Media Meet #112 by PBS at Northern Michigan University, 2001 (Box 149, Folder 3)
  - Michigan Works Strategic Planning, 2001 (Box 149, Folder 4)
  - On Lok Senior Health: A Neighborhood is a Good Place to Grow Old, 1996 (Box 149, Folder 5)
  - Ossabaw island: Georgia, 1993 (Box 149, Folder 6)
  - Partner Cultivating Creative Communities forum, Charlotte, NC, 2006 (Box 149, Folder 7)
    part 1 of 3; 3 copies
  - Partner Cultivating Creative Communities forum, Charlotte, NC, 2006 (Box 149, Folder 8)
    part 2 of 3; 3 copies
  - Partner Cultivating Creative Communities forum, Charlotte, NC, 2006 (Box 149, Folder 9)
    part 3 of 3
  - Partners for Livable Communities Telelvsion Coverage - June 13-16, 1994 (Box 149, Folder 10)
  - Presentation from New Channel 8, Washington DC for PLC, 1995 (Box 149, Folder 11)
  - Recognition of Dan Sweat, 1996 (Box 150, Folder 1)
  - Small Town, Big Dreams: The Festival ARTREACH Story, 1996 (Box 150, Folder 2)
  - Symposium of the Great projects for Great Cities, 1991 (Box 150, Folder 3)
  - The National Press Club, April 20, 2004 (Box 150, Folder 4)
    3 copies
  - There's No Place Like Home: Promoting Independence for Older Adults, 1999 (Box 150, Folder 5)
  - Trends in Arlington Worksop - 11/30/1993 (Box 150, Folder 6)
  - Turning Culture Into Community with Robert McNulty, 1998 (Box 150, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Mountain Housing, 1999 (Box 150, Folder 8)
  - Vision 20/20, 1994 (Box 150, Folder 9)
  - America's Most Livable Awards Ceremony, 2004 (Box 151, Folder 1)
  - City Assets (Presentation Quality), 1985 (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - City Videos, 1986 (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Lyons Opus 92, 1992 (Box 152, Folder 2)
  - A Celebration of Vision and Community Spirit 2006 (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting, May 12, 2009 (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - Bill Reilly Intro, 2000 (Box 153, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting Audio, undated (Box 153, Folder 4)
  - Cathy Bessant Message, 2006 (Box 153, Folder 5)
  - Charlotte Presentations, undated (Box 153, Folder 6)
  - Culivating Creative Communities: Morning Session, 2006 (Box 153, Folder 7)
    part 1 of 2; 7 copies
  - Culivating Creative Communities: Morning Session, 2006 (Box 153, Folder 8)
    part 2 of 2; 7 copies
  - Culivating Creative Communities, 2006 (Box 153, Folder 9)
    part 1 of 3; 4 copies
  - Culivating Creative Communities, 2006 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    part 2 of 3: 4 copies
  - Culivating Creative Communities, 2006 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    part 3 of 3; 4 copies
  - Culture Builds Florida PowerPoint, 2005 (Box 153, Folder 12)
  - Green Plus Awards 2011 (Box 153, Folder 13)
  - Harris Ranch Specific Plansand SPO1 Amendments 2009 (Box 153, Folder 14)
  - Honors 2006 (Box 153, Folder 15)
  - John Lewis Memorial, 2008 (Box 153, Folder 16)
  - Livable Communities Report, undated (Box 153, Folder 17)
  - NBC Nightly News; Segment on Aging in Buffalo, 2007 (Box 153, Folder 18)
  - PCYC Naples 2006 (Box 153, Folder 19)
  - Plans 4/10/07, 2007 (Box 153, Folder 20)
  - Smart City, 2001 (Box 153, Folder 21)
  - The 34 Great Waterfront of the World and What San Diego May Learn From Them, 2006 (Box 153, Folder 22)
  - Tuscaloosa Documents, 2008 (Box 153, Folder 23)
  - A New Vision for Public Libraries, 2000 (Box 153, Folder 24)
  - Genoa 92 Concept Plan, 1992 (Box 153, Folder 25)
  - Partners for Livable Communities Global Agenda, 2000 (Box 153, Folder 26)
  - Rebuilding American Communities: Reinvestment by Design, 1995 (Box 153, Folder 27)
  - Report to Metro Visions: Kick Off Forum Summary of Responses Fayetteville, Arkansas, 1990 (Box 153, Folder 28)
  - Shaping Growth in American Communities: CAMDEN Proposals and Budgets, 1989 (Box 153, Folder 29)
  - State of the Region Forum, 1991 (Box 153, Folder 30)
  - fotobriceno: Partners Bridge Builders June 30, 2004 (Box 154, Folder 1)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, April 10, 2008 (Box 154, Folder 2)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, April 20, 2004 (Box 154, Folder 3)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, April 4, 2006 (Box 154, Folder 4)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, December 1, 2005 (Box 154, Folder 5)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, December 8, 2004 (Box 154, Folder 6)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, March 5, 2008 (Box 154, Folder 7)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, March 9, 2006 (Box 154, Folder 8)
  - Markets Presentation, 2002 (Box 154, Folder 9)
  - Queens Botanical Garden Photos, undated (Box 154, Folder 10)
  - ArtShow 2, 2005 (Box 154, Folder 11)
  - Caracas: The Informal City, 2009 (Box 154, Folder 12)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, 2009 December 7 (Box 154, Folder 13)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, 2009 March 7, 2010 (Box 154, Folder 14)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, 2010 December 7 (Box 154, Folder 15)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, 2010 September 22, 2011 (Box 154, Folder 16)
  - fotobriceno: Partners, 2011 March 6 (Box 154, Folder 17)
  - Michigan's Marquette County, 2004 (Box 154, Folder 18)
  - Historic Shipwrecks: Issues in Management, 1988 (Box 154, Folder 19)
  - Arts Space and Economic Development Experience in Six Cities, undated (Box 154, Folder 20)
  - Communications as Engagement: Communications Strategy for Revitalization, 1994 (Box 154, Folder 21)
  - Crossing the Line: National Leadership Forum on Regional Strategies, 1999 (Box 154, Folder 22)
  - Cultural Heritage Tourism: A Vehicle for Dynamic Social and Economic Change, 2001 (Box 154, Folder 23)
  - Eastern Shore Retreat, 1995 (Box 154, Folder 24)
  - Environmental Tourism: Understanding Resource Conflicts Bonaire, Netherlands Antilles, 1994 (Box 154, Folder 25)
  - Family Investment Startegies: Improving the Lives of Children and Communities, 1994 (Box 154, Folder 26)
  - Memphis: Photos and various articles, undated (Box 154, Folder 27)
  - Partners' 25th Anniversary Program, 2000 (Box 154, Folder 28)
  - Report to the Cultural Plan Study Committee; Charlotte, NC, 2006 (Box 154, Folder 29)
  - Shaping Growth in American Communities: CAMDEN Proposals and Budgets, 1989 (Box 154, Folder 30)
  - Urban Action Seminar Transcript, 1977 (Box 154, Folder 31)
  - Vision for the Anacostia Watershed Leadership Forum, 1993 (Box 154, Folder 32)
  - What is Livability?, 1999 (Box 154, Folder 33)
- Series 10: Oversized, 1973-2008; (3 boxes; 3 oversize folders)
  Series 10 contains oversized materials. Most of these resources are posters created for Partners' various programs, regional newspaper articles focused on community growth, and large books published by various private companies.
  - Crossing the Line: The New Regional Dynamics, 2007 (Oversize mapcase)
  - Neighborhood Conservation/Cities Are Neighborhoods Poster, 1978 (Oversize mapcase)
  - Union County Comprehensive Plan, undated (Oversize mapcase)
  - Neighborhood Conservation/Cities Are Neighborhoods Books and Supplemental Material, 1978 (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Livbility videotape, 1978 (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Urban Life coaster, undated (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Cultivating Creative Communities Conference: Take Home Canvass Bag, 2007 (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - Albuquerque Journal: Adobe Churches Speak of Past, 1991 (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - Florida: Paradise Regained, 1985 (Box 156, Folder 5)
  - New York Times: Critics Rise Up Against Environmental Education, 1978 (Box 156, Folder 6)
  - Rebuilding Helena, 1992 (Box 156, Folder 7)
  - Washington Post: Currents of Change, 1996 (Box 156, Folder 8)
  - Charlotte Cultural Planning Focus Groups Responses, 2006 (Box 157, Folder 1)
  - Chattanooga In Motion, 1981 (Box 157, Folder 2)
  - Day Night Life Death Hope, 2008 (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Downtown Development Plan Poster, 1982 (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Dublin Community Plan: Visioning Report, 1996 (Box 157, Folder 5)
  - Les Actes de Desseins sur Montreal, 1978 (Box 157, Folder 6)
  - Second Federal Design Assembly: The Design Reality, 1973 (Box 157, Folder 7)
  - Temporary Paradise? A Look at the Special Landscape of the San Diego Region, 1974 (Box 157, Folder 8)
  - The Chicago Split and How To Avoid It, 1979 (Box 157, Folder 9)
  - Vision Plan (50-year) for the Downtown Area of Sarasota, Florida Poster, 1986 (Box 157, Folder 10)
  - We Make Television Worth Watching, 1987 (Box 157, Folder 11)